Omaha Indian interviews collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound Recordings, 26 7-inch reels, 1 60-minute audiocassette.
  - Interview of Rufus White conducted by Alan Jabbour and Laurel McIntyre regarding recordings from AFC 1986/038, AFC 1948/123, and AFC 1985/015, July 20-23, 1999, 25 sound tape reels
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1983 Omaha pow-wow songs, July 21, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR012)
      Includes playback of and commmentary on Little Boys’ Fancy Dance, Tiny Tots’ Traditional Cloth Dance, Little Girls’ Traditional Cloth Dance, Junior Girls’ Traditional Cloth Dance, Little Boys’ Traditional Dance (Call Numbers: AFC 1986/038: 0498, 0502, 0504, 0506-0507, 0511, 0513).
      - Commentary on Tiny Tots' Traditional Cloth Dance Contest Song (Warm-Up) (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0501), AFC 1999/014: 0796
        Rufus White translates the song: "The people are making a circle and are protecting their little ones." ("This is just what buffalo do.").
      - Commentary on Tiny Tots' Traditional Dance Contest Song (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0511), AFC 1999/014: 0797
        Rufus White translates the song: "You're saying the things that I'm hollering out to you. You're praising us." Notes from interview: This song, like other contest songs, is relevant to specific age groups. Even if the contest song does not have words, it does have meaning.
      - Commentary on Little Boys' Traditional Dance Contest Song (Warm-Up) (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0513), AFC 1999/014: 0798
        Rufus White translates the song: "When you dance, make noise out there. Put your feet out there and run. Make all the noise you can." Notes from interview: This is a song without words.
      - Commentary on Junior Boys' Traditional Dance Contest Song (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0516), AFC 1999/014: 0799
      - Commentary on Warm-Up Song for Dancers (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0518), AFC 1999/014: 0800
      - Commentary on General Dancing Song (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0520), AFC 1999/014: 0801
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1983 Omaha pow-wow songs, July 22, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR013)
      Includes playback of and commmentary on Giveaway Song, Grand Finale, Grand Entry, Flag Song, Whipman’s Song, Tail Dancer’s Song, Junior Boys’ Traditional Dance, Women’s Shawl, Women’s Traditional Cloth Dance (Call Numbers: AFC 1986/038: 0523, 0526, 0537-0542, 0544-0545, 0554, 0557-0558, 0560-0561, 0563-0564).
      - Commentary on Giveaway Song (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0523), AFC 1999/014: 0802
        Notes from interview: This is one of the oldest songs that is still sung by the Omahas. This is a song without words, with the exception of "sage." (Sage is used in the Native American Church.)
      - Commentary on Junior Boys' Traditional Dance Contest Song (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0558), AFC 1999/014: 0803
        Rufus White translates the song: "I'm coming into the arena. Watch me." Notes from interview: This is an old traditional song that was saved for a contest song during the pow-wow.
      - Commentary on Women's Traditional Cloth Dance Contest Song (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0564), AFC 1999/014: 0804
        Rufus White translates the song: "He was riding a horse. He fell off the horse, and then he started running. The horses are waiting, and we have just returned from war. I'm coming. Look at me."
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1983 Omaha pow-wow songs, July 22, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR014)
      Includes playback of and commmentary on Women’s Traditional Buckskin Dance, Sneak Up, Memorial Song for Mr. and Mrs. John Turner (Call Numbers: AFC 1986/038: 0567-0569, 0572-0573).
      - Commentary on Women's Traditional Buckskin Dance Contest Song (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0568), AFC 1999/014: 0805
        Rufus White translates the song: "Another tribe is standing there."
      - Commentary on Memorial Song for Mr. and Mrs. John Turner (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0572), AFC 1999/014: 0806
      - Commentary on Family Song of John and Susette Turner (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0573), AFC 1999/014: 0807
        Notes from interview: John Turner made this song for his children. Many families have their own songs that are used during specials.
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1983 Omaha pow-wow songs, July 23, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR015)
      Includes playback of and commmentary on Flute Song, Hethu’shka Song, Contest Song, Women’s Shawl Contest, Women’s Traditional Coth Dance, Fancy Dancers’ Songs. (Call Numbers: AFC 1986/038: 0576-0580, 0583, 0585, 0587, 0590-0593)
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1983 Omaha pow-wow songs, July 23, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR016)
      Includes playback of and commmentary on Fancy Dancers’ Contest Song, Traditional Dancers’ Contest Song, Contest Songs, Veterans Song, Farewell Song (Call Numbers: AFC 1986/038: 0594-0595, 0599-0600, 0603-0611, 0613, 0616).
      - Commentary on Farewell Song (Call Number: AFC 1986/038: 0616), AFC 1999/014: 0808
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1983 Omaha pow-wow songs, July 23, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR017)
      Includes playback of and commmentary on Family Song, Flag Song, Grand Finale Song, Grand Entry Song, Hethu’shka, Whipman’s Song, Tail Dancer’s Song, Song for Two Tail Dancers (Call Numbers: AFC 1986/038: 0619, 0621-0622, 0627-0632, 0635-0636, 0639).
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1983 Omaha pow-wow songs, July 23, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR018)
      Includes playback of and commmentary on Green Corn Dance Song, Hethu’shka, Pow-wow Princess Candidate Song, Contest Song for Clowns, Men’s Fancy Dance Contest Song, Men’s Traditional Contest Song (Call Numbers: AFC 1986/038: 0643, 0645-0647, 0651, 0653, 0655, 0657-0658, 0661).
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1983 Omaha pow-wow songs, July 23, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR019)
      Includes playback of and commmentary on Men’s Traditional Contest Song, Fancy Dance Songs, Contest Song for Clowns, Whipman’s Song, Song during Joe Harlan Jr. Special, Contest Song, Traditional Song for Everybody, announcement of Pow-wow Princess, an unidentified song (Call Numbers: AFC 1986/038: 0662, 0664-0665, 0668-0672, 0674-0675, 0679, 0683, 0687-0688, 0690, 0692, 0696-0697).
    - Rufus White’s commentary pertaining to the ten Hethu’shka songs that are included on “Omaha Indian Music” (AFC L71), July 22, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR020)
    - Omaha language translations by Rufus White continued., July 23, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR021)
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1985 Neptune Plaza Concert, July 22, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR022)
      Up to 3rd Hethu’shka song.
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1985 Neptune Plaza Concert, July 22, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR023)
      Neptune Plaza Concert continued. 4th Hethu’shka song with commentary by Tribal Council Chairman Elmer Blackbird and Rufus White. Chairman Blackbird also talks about the Omaha language and provides biographical information about himself.
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1985 Neptune Plaza Concert and Omaha language translations of 1983 pow-wow, July 23, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR024)
      Neptune Plaza Concert continued. Hollis Stabler’s story, most of first Hethu’shka song (38:28 on side B). Rufus White’s translations of Omaha spoken during the 1983 pow-wow and commentary.
    - Rufus White’s commentary on 1985 Neptune Plaza Concert and Omaha language translations of 1983 pow-wow, July 23, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR025)
      Neptune Plaza Concert continued. Tail of first Hethu’shka song on Side B, Sneak Up, Buffalo Dance, Quitting Song, closing remarks/story by Rufus White and continued Omaha language translations of 1983 pow-wow with commentary.
  - Interview of Morgan Lovejoy interview conducted by Alan Jabbour and Laurel McIntyre regarding recordings from AFC 1985/015, August 15, 1999, 1 sound tape reel
    Morgan Lovejoy comments on the invocation he delivered at the 1985 Library of Congress concert and then provides biographical information about himself. (In providing biographical information, he concentrated on his discovering that he had tuberculosis (in the fifth grade), his experience in WWII, and his job as a groundskeeper.)
    - Morgan Lovejoy commentary on his invocation at 1985 Neptune Plaza Concert, August 15, 1999, sound tape reel, analog, 3 3/4 ips; 7 in. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR026)
  - Interview of Rufus White conducted by Alan Jabbour and Laurel McIntyre regarding recordings from AFC 1983/026, October 17, 1999, 1 audio cassette
    Rufus White translates the introduction that John Turner gave during the February 24, 1983 interview with Alan Jabbour. In addition, Rufus tells about how he (Rufus) learned to sing and play the drum.
    - Rufus White translates the introduction that John Turner gave during the February 24, 1983 interview with Alan Jabbour, October 17, 1999, 60-minute audio cassette. (Tape AFC 1999/014: SR027)
- Series 3: Graphic Materials, 8 pages of description, 5 contact sheets, 184 black and white negatives, 22 black and white 8x10 prints, 2 posters
  - Photographs—Logs, 8 pages, 5 contact sheets (Box-folder 1/11)
    Description of photographs regarding trip to Macy, Nebraska and work done at Library of Congress with contact sheets
  - Photographs—Negatives, April 11, 1999-October 17, 1999, 5 sheets, 184 negatives; AFC 1999/014: PH001-184 (Box-folder 1/12)
    Images of American Folklife Center staff, Omaha tribal informants, during April through October 1999 trips to Macy, Nebraska as well as work spaces at the Library of Congress Photographed people include: Chairman Elmer Blackbird, Alan Jabbour, Rufus White, Nato Merrill, Dennis Hastings, Joy Neihardt, John G. Neihardt, Robin Neihardt, Chuck Trimble, Janyce Falcon Hunt, Laurel McIntyre, Edward R. Thomas, Linda Robinson, Rudi Mitchell, Therese Dunn, Nikki Zeichner, Maxine White, Rachel Howard, Christa Maher, Tom Bramel, Nathan Georgitis, Morgan Lovejoy, Charles Lovejoy, Peggy Bulger, Jim Hardin, Peter Bartis, Doris Craig, and Nora Yeh. Primarily photographed by Laurel McIntyre.
  - Photographs—Prints, 9 prints; 86120 (Box-folder 1/13)
    Prints from April 1999 trip to Macy, Nebraska. Photographer, Laurel McIntyre unless otherwise noted.
    - Alan Jabbour and Rufus White in Tribal Administration Building, April 12, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH004
    - Alan Jabbour, Rufus White, and Nato Merrill in Tribal Administration Building, April 12, 1999, 2 black and white 8 x 10 prints; AFC 1999/014: PH005
    - Alan Jabbour and Dennis Hastings in library at Nebraska Indian Community College, Omaha branch, April 12, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH013
    - Dennis Hastings in library at Nebraska Indian Community College, Omaha branch, April 12, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH014
    - Bancroft Cemetery with La Flesche grave sites, April 11, 1999, 2 black and white 8 x 10 prints; AFC 1999/014: PH023
    - Joy Neihardt, Laural McIntyre, and Janyce Falcon Hunt at the Neihardt Center, April 11, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH027
      Photographer, Alan Jabbour
    - Chuck Trimble, Robin Neihardt, Janyce Falcon Hunt, and Alan Jabbour at the Neihardt Center, April 11, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH028
  - Photographs—Prints, 7 prints; BR199- BR205 (Box-folder 1/14)
    Prints from July 1999 trip to Macy, Nebraska. Photographer, Laurel McIntyre.
    - Chairman Elmer Blackbird and Alan Jabbour in meeting room, Omaha Tribal Administration Building, July 22, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH043
    - Alan Jabbour and Rufus White in meeting room, Omaha Tribal Administration Building, July 22, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH048
    - Rufus White in meeting room, Omaha Tribal Administration Building, July 22, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH050
    - Rufus White and Alan Jabbour in meeting room, Omaha Tribal Administration Building, July 22, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH053
    - Rufus White in meeting room, Omaha Tribal Administration Building, July 22, 1999, 3 black and white 8 x 10 prints; AFC 1999/014: PH054, 56, 59
  - Photographs—Prints, 2 prints; 1-87158 (Box-folder 1/15)
    Prints from August 1999 trip to Macy, Nebraska. Photographer, Laurel McIntyre.
    - Omaha Harvest Celebration Pow-wow, August 13, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH083
    - Macy, Nebraska, cemetery, August 12, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH111
  - Photographs—Prints, 4 prints; 2-87158 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Morgan Lovejoy at the Lovejoy residence, Omaha, August 15, 1999, 2 black and white 8 x 10 prints; AFC 1999/014: PH140
    - Alan Jabbour, Morgan Lovejoy, and Charles Lovejoy at the Lovejoy residence, Omaha, August 15, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH142
    - Alan Jabbour and Morgan Lovejoy at the Lovejoy residence, Omaha, August 15, 1999, 1 black and white 8 x 10 print; AFC 1999/014: PH147
  - Posters, 2 posters (Box 2)
    Related material: Poster copies
    - Poster - 1st Fundraising Handgame with Rufus White as head singer, August 9, 1999, AFC 1999/014: GR001; 8.5 x 14 inches
    - Poster - 195th Hethushka [sic] Annual Pow-Wow, August 12-15, 1999, AFC 1999/014: GR002; 11 x 17 inches
- Series 4: Electronic Media, 1 computer zip disk.
  - Electronic Media—Zip Disk., August 22, 2000., 1 computer zip disk.; AFC 1999/014: CF001 (Box-folder 1/17)
    Administrative files related to the creation and processing of the collection.